Hi, I'm *Michael Dawson*. I help companies to build kick-ass products and engineering departments.

With over 10 years experience designing, building and maintaining software, most recently I've led development for a 30x annual-growth startup, designing systems using Ruby/Rails, GraphQL, Typescript, React, and more. I also help bring a startup mindset to engineering, drawing on experience investing in and supporting high-growth startups, and passion for processes like Dual-Track development to maximise learning.

Skills / Highlights

Ruby / Rails, React / Web Components, Typescript Webpack, Rspec / Capybara / Cypress, TDD, Databases, Elasticsearch, AWS, Web components, React Native, Serverless, Software design patterns, Dual track software

Education

Bachelor of Innovation and Entrepreneurship Adelaide University

Graduate Certificate, Enterprise Development TAFE SA

Experience

Lead Engineer, AirRobe - Sep 2020-present

Architecting and developing systems, mentoring other team members, supporting hiring, helping to facilitate growth. Helping to implement dual-track software development - separating discovery efforts intended to maximise speed of learning from core development efforts intended to optimise quality / stability. Ruby / Rails, React, Typescript, Webpack, Web Components, GraphQL, AWS

Investor and Member, Hitchhiker VC - 2020-present

Investing in startups with high growth potential; supporting investment companies wherever possible

Founder and full-stack developer, ActionPact / BJJ.Al, 2019-2020

Exploring opportunities with task scheduling, as well as visualisation of Jiu Jitsu techniques (two separate projects). React Native, Ruby / Rails, GraphQL, Google Firebase

Development team lead / Lead Ruby Architect, Marketplacer - 2017- 2019

Leading the data integrations team and project teams for new systems. Helping to establish best-practices for Ruby / Rails software development, running the regular Ruby meetup. Ruby / Rails, React, GraphQL

Web Developer, Vinomofo — 2014-2016

Developing software that helped to support a young company's growth to a \$100m valuation. *Ruby / Rails, React, Elasticsearch*

Director and investor, Silicon Balls — 2016-2020

Helping to develop systems and on-board investors, and make 10 early-stage tech investments.

Co-founder and lead developer, Beyond Content — 2013-2015

Helping to establish the Brandy Content creative agency (now Beyond Content), overseeing and implementing digital and creative projects. *Ruby / Rails*

Client Account Services, Australian Taxation Office 2010-2013

Developing software macros for manual workflows. Awarded the Commissioner's award for Innovation. *Visual Basic, Oracle/Siebel Enterprise Software*

Feel free to drop me a line!

hi@michaeldawson.com.au